SHRADDHA TRIPATHI

Email: shrradhatripathii@gmail.com | Mobile No: +91-7208454524 Sanpada Navi Mumbai

A core academician and researcher having 5+ with an entrepreneurial vision to simplify research and engineering activities. Effective team contributor, digital enthusiastic who identifies and leverages assets in teammates to reach organizational goals. Optimist who believes there is no failure, only feedback.

Work Experience

Maya Institute of Technology, Uttarakhand Technical University, Dehradun

01 Feb 2014-30 June 2015

Assistant Professor, Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering

- Academic activities for B.Tech & M.Tech of Electronics and Electrical Engineering.
- SODH Coordinator: an Initiative of R&D, MITM; for Internal Research Facilitation; for prototype development.
- RISE Coordinator and In charge for Engineering projects.
- To evaluate applications of the Students (B.Tech, M.Tech) and of faculties towards collaborating for external project work.
- To Support R&D department, Research Group of Department in formulating interconnected National and International programs, project report, projects, collaborative research projects, conference etc.
- Coordinator and In Charge for Embedded, IoT and AI R&D section of the department.

National Institute of Engineering and Technology, UPTU, Greater Noida

09 Sep 2013-11 Jan 2014

Lecturer, Department of Electronics and Communication Engineering

- Academic activities for B.Tech of Electronics and Electrical Engineering
- To support R&D activities, project and other activities like seminar, conferences etc

Kumaon Engineering College, Almora, Uttarakhand Technical University

Sep 2011 to 30Aug 2013

Teaching Assistant, Research Scholar

- Academic activities for B.Tech of Electronics and Electrical Engineering
- Core Subject: DIGITAL COMMUNICATION
- Development of a practical sessions and modules.
- Initiated various programs and initatives for the core tech driven program.
- To formulate the policy document, patent document and resourceful article.
- To support and initiate the International Conferences and Seminars

Entrepreneurial skills

Co-Founder, Quirky woman Shraddha Tripathi:life as a mom and wife

2017 till present

- Co-Founded, Quirky Mother, https://www.shraddhatripathi89.com/ an online blogging which shares information and contents on health's, parenting, women and on latest issues towards newly parents.
- Published various articles on women health, social factors, challenges and health complication which needs to be taken care by women post delivery.
- Chalked out initial strategy to communicate with people to talk on various social taboos and developed the blog as a brand
- ♦ Increased the user visibility from Zero to 1K+ per month unique visitors and generated revenue through various social media and advertisement.
- Actively looks after social media outreach and initiatives.

Skills & Competencies

- Interactive and Imaginative on presentation, digital platforms and on development process.
- Primary and Secondary Marketing Strategies, Excellent problem-solving skills.
- Deep technical background in research and innovation.
- Goal Oriented, Motivated team player with excellent public speaking ability and interpersonal communication.

- Initiator and problem-solver using creativity, resourcefulness, and assets to break down and overcome obstacles.
- Attentive listener who is not afraid to incorporate the opinions of valued team members into policy and planning.
- Long term thinking, future oriented

Educational Experience

Degree / Examination	Year	Institute / School	Performance
M.Tech (Digital Electronics & Communication System)	2011-13	Kumaon Engineering College, Uttarakhand	80%
		Technical University, Uttarakhand	
B.Tech (Electronics and Communication Engineering)	2006-10	IMS Engineering College	72.88%
HSC	2005	UP College, UP Board	77%
SSC	2003	UP Board	69%

- GATE 2016 Qualified with Score 359
- GATE 2011 Qualified with Score 366

Research Work

♦ M.Tech Dissertation

Objective: Automatic Detection of Exudates in Retinal Fundus Images using Differential Morphological Profile

Description: Research work on automatic method for exudate detection from color fundus images based on Differential Morphological Profile (DMP). The detection of exudates is important for the diagnosis of eye diseases such as diabetic retinopathy

❖ B.Tech PROJECT

Title: "A Method to Design A Pulse Shape for UltraWideBand Communications"

Environment: Matlab

❖ SUMMER INTERNSHIP

o Organization: NOKIA SIEMENS NETWORKS (June'09-August'09) on GSM and Satellite communication

Subject Taught

- POC[Principles of Communication]
- D.Com[Digital Communication]
- DSP[Digital Signal Processing]

Research Paper and Conferences

- ❖ K. K. Singh, A. Singh, S.Tripathi and P. Khandelwal, "Blood Vessel Extraction For Retinal Images Using Morphological Operator and KCN Clustering", Advance Computing Conference (IACC), 2014 IEEE International, pp.1142-1146, 21-22 Feb. 2014
- S. Tripathi, K. K. Singh, B. K. Singh and A. Singh, "Automatic Detection of Exudates in Retinal Fundus Images using Differential Morphological Profile," International Journal of Engineering & Technology, vol. 5, no. 2, June, 2013.
- S. Tripathi, K. Kumar, B. K. Singh and R. P. Singh, "Image Segmentation: A Review," International Journal of Computer Science and Management Research, vol. 1, no. 4, pp.838-843, November, 2012.
- Thesis is published as a book in LAP LAMBERT Academic Publishing.
- S. Tripathi, K. K. Singh, B. K. Singh and A. Singh, "Automatic Detection of Exudates in Retinal Fundus Images using Differential Morphological Profile," LAP LAMBERT Academic Publishing, ISBN:978-3-659-54961-8, 2014.

Extra Curricular Activities

- Won first prize in Dance competition at school level.
- Class Representative from 6th to 12th class in U.P. College, Varanasi.
- ❖ Won third prize in Dance competition in Inter College Fest "MELANGE 07"
- Coordinated various events in school and college level.

- ❖ Volunteer in National Conference cum Seminar (2008).
- Blogger

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to the best of my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned.

Place: Maharashtra (Shraddha Tripathi)